<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on The Median Duck</title>
    <link>https://bluevolvo87.github.io/themedianduck/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on The Median Duck</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© Christopher Nam</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://bluevolvo87.github.io/themedianduck/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Foulest Mouth of Them All</title>
      <link>https://bluevolvo87.github.io/themedianduck/2024/10/profanity-insanity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://bluevolvo87.github.io/themedianduck/2024/10/profanity-insanity/</guid>
      <description>Your Task&#xD;Profanity Insanity&#xD;The Foulest Mouth of Them All…&#xD;What Have We Learnt Today?&#xD;💡 Warning This Post Contains Strong Language...Reader Discretion is advised! Your Task&#xD;Find the foulest mouthed contestant in UK Taskmaster to date.&#xD;Bonus points for finding the foulest mouth in each series.&#xA;A Side Amble in the Preamble&#xD;In the spirit of good code practices, namely avoiding duplicating code and centralising common code into a single location were possible, here is a set of preamble scripts that I will be sourcing at the beginning of each post.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Data Dic(tionary) pic of TdlM</title>
      <link>https://bluevolvo87.github.io/themedianduck/2024/08/tdlm-data-dictionary/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://bluevolvo87.github.io/themedianduck/2024/08/tdlm-data-dictionary/</guid>
      <description>Your Task&#xD;Don’t be a Data Dic (tionary) about this…&#xD;Summary of Findings&#xD;Final Thoughts&#xD;Appendix Details&#xD;Your Task&#xD;Obtain a good overview of the tables in the TdLM database, what these tables contain, how these tables are linked together, and which ones are the most important for this project.&#xA;Don’t be a Data Dic (tionary) about this…&#xD;This article assumes that you are able to connect to the TdlM database successfully (database connection post).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sidenote: Musings on TdlM</title>
      <link>https://bluevolvo87.github.io/themedianduck/2024/07/data-quality-musings/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://bluevolvo87.github.io/themedianduck/2024/07/data-quality-musings/</guid>
      <description>Sidenote Introduction&#xD;Data Quality&#xD;Why This Datasource?&#xD;Potential Articles to Explore in the Future&#xD;Sidenote Introduction&#xD;A few remarks and musings on the Trabajo de las Mesas database (TdlM).&#xA;Data Quality&#xD;As with any analysis and modelling project, the insights and conclusions generated are only as good as the data supplied to it.&#xA;I do not know the specifics regarding how this data is collated and reviewed (my intention is that there will be a future article dedicated to this), but believe the data is inputted by fellow (hardcore) Taskmaster fans from taskmaster.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Strength in Data: Connecting to the Taskmaster Database</title>
      <link>https://bluevolvo87.github.io/themedianduck/2024/07/database-connection/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://bluevolvo87.github.io/themedianduck/2024/07/database-connection/</guid>
      <description>Your Task Successfully connect to the Taskmaster database from within R. Fastest wins; your time starts now!&#xA;This article provides an overview of Trabajo de las Mesas, a pivotal database that will be central to this project.&#xA;The article will also provide guidance on how to connect to the database from within R.&#xA;Trabajo de las Mesas Database Trabajo de las Mesas (TdlM 1) provides a plethora of data associated with Taskmaster in a database format.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
