<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on The Median Duck</title>
    <link>https://bluevolvo87.github.io/themedianduck/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on The Median Duck</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© Christopher Nam</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 28 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://bluevolvo87.github.io/themedianduck/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>May the Odds Be In Your Favour</title>
      <link>https://bluevolvo87.github.io/themedianduck/2025/06/odds-in-your-favour/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://bluevolvo87.github.io/themedianduck/2025/06/odds-in-your-favour/</guid>
      <description>Your Task&#xD;A New Dawn, A New Dataset&#xD;The Observed Reality Timeline Approach (ORT)&#xD;The Multiverse Approach (MV)&#xD;What Have We Learnt Today&#xD;Your Task&#xD;For each contestant of the Series 19 of UK Taskmater, generate probability distributions on their ranking in an episode.&#xA;For example, estimate the probability of Fatiha-El Ghorri placing 1st, 2nd, 3rd, 4th and 5th in an episode of Series 19.&#xA;A New Dawn, A New Dataset&#xD;With Series 19 well underway (at time of writing, Episode 8 “Science all your life” has just broadcasted), and a potential lag in the data being supplied to TdlM database1, it is time to take data matters into our own piano capable hands.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Elephant in the Room</title>
      <link>https://bluevolvo87.github.io/themedianduck/2025/06/the-elephant-in-the-room/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://bluevolvo87.github.io/themedianduck/2025/06/the-elephant-in-the-room/</guid>
      <description>The Elephant&#xD;The Room: Series 19 Opinion (so far)&#xD;The Elephant&#xD;Hello. It’s been a while and I apologise to my single digit audience for my absence.&#xD;I would love to say that I had a good excuse for my absence, but the truth is rather more boring than that.&#xA;However, it’s time embrace the free time the I have regained and reignite this (passion) project.&#xA;The simple truth is that the Board volunteer position I held for the Housing Association associated with my condominium (a flat for UK readers) took over a significant proportion of my time and energy.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Taskmaster Swear Cloud Appreciation Society</title>
      <link>https://bluevolvo87.github.io/themedianduck/2024/11/taskmaster-swear-cloud/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://bluevolvo87.github.io/themedianduck/2024/11/taskmaster-swear-cloud/</guid>
      <description>Your Task&#xD;Making it Rain… with Data&#xD;The Overall Swear Forecast&#xD;The Series Swear Forecast&#xD;Getting My Head out of the Clouds, and Going to the Bar.&#xD;What Have we Learnt Today?&#xD;This post contains strong lanuage…reader discretion advised! And this time, I really mean it…&#xA;Your Task&#xD;Create a swear word cloud which is fit for the Cloud Appreciation Society.&#xA;Making it Rain… with Data&#xD;We continue to use the profanity based queries we have developed in the following posts (Foulest Mouth of Them All, The Taskmaster’s Potty Mouth).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Taskmaster&#39;s Potty Mouth</title>
      <link>https://bluevolvo87.github.io/themedianduck/2024/11/the-taskmaster-s-potty-mouth/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://bluevolvo87.github.io/themedianduck/2024/11/the-taskmaster-s-potty-mouth/</guid>
      <description>Your Task&#xD;The Profanity Rate Approach&#xD;Case of the Missing Profanities&#xD;Putting on a Spread&#xD;To Mean or Median…&#xD;What Have We Learnt Today?&#xD;💡 Warning This Post Contains Strong Language...Reader Discretion is advised! Your Task&#xD;Find out whether the Taskmaster (Greg Davies) has become more or less foul mouth over time.&#xD;This post is an extension of this profanity based post.&#xA;The Profanity Rate Approach&#xD;One way to answer our question is to use Profanity Rate that we previously defined in the aforementioned post.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Foulest Mouth of Them All</title>
      <link>https://bluevolvo87.github.io/themedianduck/2024/10/profanity-insanity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://bluevolvo87.github.io/themedianduck/2024/10/profanity-insanity/</guid>
      <description>Your Task&#xD;Profanity Insanity&#xD;The Foulest Mouth of Them All…&#xD;What Have We Learnt Today?&#xD;💡 Warning This Post Contains Strong Language...Reader Discretion is advised! Your Task&#xD;Find the foulest mouthed contestant in UK Taskmaster to date.&#xD;Bonus points for finding the foulest mouth in each series.&#xA;A Side Amble in the Preamble&#xD;In the spirit of good code practices, namely avoiding duplicating code and centralising common code into a single location were possible, here is a set of preamble scripts that I will be sourcing at the beginning of each post.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Data Dic(tionary) pic of TdlM</title>
      <link>https://bluevolvo87.github.io/themedianduck/2024/08/tdlm-data-dictionary/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://bluevolvo87.github.io/themedianduck/2024/08/tdlm-data-dictionary/</guid>
      <description>Your Task&#xD;Don’t be a Data Dic (tionary) about this…&#xD;Summary of Findings&#xD;Final Thoughts&#xD;Appendix Details&#xD;Your Task&#xD;Obtain a good overview of the tables in the TdLM database, what these tables contain, how these tables are linked together, and which ones are the most important for this project.&#xA;Don’t be a Data Dic (tionary) about this…&#xD;This article assumes that you are able to connect to the TdlM database successfully (database connection post).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sidenote: Musings on TdlM</title>
      <link>https://bluevolvo87.github.io/themedianduck/2024/07/data-quality-musings/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://bluevolvo87.github.io/themedianduck/2024/07/data-quality-musings/</guid>
      <description>Sidenote Introduction&#xD;Data Quality&#xD;Why This Datasource?&#xD;Potential Articles to Explore in the Future&#xD;Sidenote Introduction&#xD;A few remarks and musings on the Trabajo de las Mesas database (TdlM).&#xA;Data Quality&#xD;As with any analysis and modelling project, the insights and conclusions generated are only as good as the data supplied to it.&#xA;I do not know the specifics regarding how this data is collated and reviewed (my intention is that there will be a future article dedicated to this), but believe the data is inputted by fellow (hardcore) Taskmaster fans from taskmaster.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Strength in Data: Connecting to the Taskmaster Database</title>
      <link>https://bluevolvo87.github.io/themedianduck/2024/07/database-connection/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://bluevolvo87.github.io/themedianduck/2024/07/database-connection/</guid>
      <description>Your Task Successfully connect to the Taskmaster database from within R. Fastest wins; your time starts now!&#xA;This article provides an overview of Trabajo de las Mesas, a pivotal database that will be central to this project.&#xA;The article will also provide guidance on how to connect to the database from within R.&#xA;Trabajo de las Mesas Database Trabajo de las Mesas (TdlM 1) provides a plethora of data associated with Taskmaster in a database format.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
